Are you also going to get your health insurance,
but you are also confused about
which health insurance you should
take here and one mistake of yours can cause you a
loss of thousands. In this video,
we
will compare the top health insurance companies of India, so
here I guarantee you that
after watching this video, all your
doubts will be cleared and you will be
able to choose the best plan for yourself and how
you can also reduce your premium. I will
explain everything here in detail.
First of all, here we will compare AC Ego's
Optima Secure, ICC Lunt's 11 Plan,
Money Pay, Cigna's Sarv Uttam Plan, Bajaj Ella's
My Health Plan and Niva B's Espai
Platinum Plus Direct.
So first of all, let's talk about sum insured, that is,
how much total cover you
can take here. Here you can take 5 lakhs,
10 lakhs, 20
lakhs, 50 lakhs. The
company pays for your cover.
Suppose you are admitted to the hospital.
So this amount will be
paid by the company, so here I have
taken a sum insured amount of Rs 10 lakh in all the companies, now let's talk about the
premium, that is, how much total premium you have to pay to the
company for the year, your premium
depends on your age and
if you already have any accompanying disease, that is,
any disease, then your
premium increases here and if your
age is also more, then your
premium also increases there, so
here my age is 25, so according to that,
you will see the premium here, the
highest of all the companies is Rs 14350 and the
lowest is seen in IC Land and
Manpal Cigna Rs 7103 and in Manpal Cigna Rs
7350, so this means that these two
are the best here and the rest are not good, so
you will not know from this, we will understand in detail later, then
you will know there, now let's talk about
room rent, here the company
provides you rooms of different categories here  It does this as you might have seen in a hospital,
in the general ward,
you get to see three-four patients in one room,
then here you get
to see a private single room in
which there is only one patient, then above it
comes the lux room in which you get to
see TV, sofa and many other things,
above this also comes the sweet room,
inside this you get to see luxury room in
which you get to see living area
and high facilities here,
but the charges for these are
also high, so here
you get to see a single private AC room,
inside ICICI Bank also you get to see a single private AC
room,
what does restoration of cover mean,
restoration of cover means that suppose
you have taken a sum issue total cover of Rs 10 lakh
and suppose you get a disease
and you get admitted in the hospital and
your hospital bill is of Rs 7 lakh, you
come back here after a month or two,
something related or unrelated happens to you.  So here you get to
see the restoration of cover, that is,
you will get the restoration of Rs. 10 lakhs again, that is,
you will get a cover of Rs. 10 lakhs here for
unlimited times, so which company provides you here, then you will
get it once more. Talking about ICC Labad,
here you get
to see unlimited cover of Rs. 10 lakhs for
both related and unrelated illnesses, that is, if the
same thing happens to you again or something else happens, then
here you
get to see the restoration of cover of Rs. 10 lakhs every time, the
same thing is seen here in Money Pay Sina, here
you can
also see it in Bajaj Ella and
you can also see it in Niva B,
which you will get only hdfcergo.com
benefit, so all the companies
provide you different benefits here according to their own,
so look carefully, first of all let's
talk
hdfc0000008 after 2 years Now let's talk about
ICICI Lamba, here every
year if you do not make any claim then
your sum insured will increase by ₹1 lakh and the maximum amount will be
10 lakh i.e.
your 10 lakh will become 20 lakh within 5 years
and suppose you make a claim in the third year then there will be no
effect on your sum insured.
Now let's talk about Money Pal Signa, the
best thing here is there is a guaranteed increase,
suppose even if you make a claim this year,
your sum insured will
remain here next year and your sum insured will increase 100%
i.e. 10 lakh will become 20 lakh next year also if
you make a claim. If we talk about Bajaj Lance,
here your sum insured will increase by ₹1 lakh every year
and the maximum will go up to 50 lakh and
if you make a claim that year then it will
not increase next year but there is a
guaranteed increase in Money Pal Signa. Now let's talk about
Niva b  Under this, your sum insured will
increase by ₹10 lakh every year and the maximum amount will
go up to 1 crore and suppose you make a
claim then next year ₹10 lakh will
not increase but your total sum
insured will remain the same, neither will it
decrease nor will it increase, so here
after looking at all the companies you came to know one thing
that Money Pal Signa is increasing it guaranteed
and
on hdfc0000050 you do not need to pay even a single rupee,
you will be paid directly through the company
here, so
which company's type is with how many hospitals, then you are
taking hdfc0003636 and if it is written on it copay
20 then it means that in your
hospital bill that will be made here, you will have to pay
20 from your pocket, so you have to keep this thing in
mind also, so here you will
see, let's
talk about pre-hospitalization, it
means that suppose you get
admitted in the hospital, before that, here
you have to pay the medical expenses of the tests that
you got done  The company also pays for the expenses.
If you have the bill,
you get the expenses of the previous 60 days here.
Now let's talk about post-
hospitalization. Suppose you are admitted to the hospital and
after that you are discharged. The
policy also bears the expenses after that. For
how many days will it bear? If we
talk about ADAC AGO, then here the
company bears the expenses for 180 days, that is,
post-hospitalization. In all other companies,
you get 180 days' expenses here.
So here you have seen
IC Lumbard
Money Pa. Cigna and Bajaj Alliance in pre- and post-hospitalization. They also give you three
days' extra pre-hospitalization
expenses. Now let's talk about day care
treatment. Suppose you are admitted to the hospital
and
you are discharged before the expiry of one day, then what will be
covered under your policy?
Here, day treatment will also
come under this policy. If you are discharged within 24 hours, then
all-day treatments are also
available here in all the companies. Now let's talk about
hospitalization at  Home cover, suppose you are
not getting beds in the hospital
due to shortage like it happened in Corona, then will
you get home cover there or
not and if you get it then up to what amount will you get, so
here in all the companies you get cover of up to 10 lakhs,
now let's talk about ambulance
charges, here you get
cover of up to 10 lakhs in all the companies,
now let's talk about initial
waiting period, suppose you
take a health insurance policy today, then will
your policy become active from the first day, will
you have to wait here or
not, in all the companies
here you have to wait for 30 days, only
after that your policy
starts here and if by chance
you have an accident then it will be covered,
apart from this, here any
disease of yours is not covered for 30 days,
now let's talk about if you
already have any disease then
how much will be your waiting period, you should always know this
before taking a health insurance policy,
whenever you take it  You have to always
tell your customers that you have this disease and if you
hide it, then when you make a claim, it gets
rejected. Suppose you smoke
and you have any disease, then tell the
other person so that your claim will
not be rejected. And if you hide it and
later when you make a claim, then your claim will be
rejected. So you have to take special
care of this thing. So when will the cover be here in all the companies?
Covered after 3 years, that is, if you are
taking a policy today, then for 3 years
if you have any pre-existing disease, it will
not be covered. It will be covered after 3 years, the
company will bear all its expenses. But after 3 years,
now let's talk about maternity cover.
What is there in it? Will the policy cover you or not in the things that happen from pregnancy to the birth of the child? So,
if you want, then you can take this cover available under Money Pal Cigna.
For that, you will have to pay a little extra premium here. You can
take maternity cover. Now we will talk about
Mid Year Member Edition. Suppose
here you have taken a single cover.  You have
taken a policy for yourself but you want to
add your child or spouse in between, can
you add it or not? So,
in HDFC AGO, if your
child's birth is between 91 to 180 days, then
you can add them after 91 days and
if you want to add your spouse, then
you can add them also after 91 days.
In ICICI Lombard, you can
add a child after 91 days but you
cannot add your spouse, that is, you
cannot add your wife.
In Sarva Uttam, here you can add both your child
and your spouse
and in this, you can add them only after the first day if you
want. There is no
waiting period in this. In Bajaj Alliance,
there is 91 days for children and here
also spout is not allowed, that is, you
cannot add your wife. In the Mid Year
Member Edition and if we talk about Niva Bhupa,
here also you can add your child.  You
can add your spouse after 90 days and if you want, you
can also add your spouse anytime. Now let's
talk about free health checkup. Suppose
you have taken a policy and you want to get
some tests done for your body like
cholesterol, ECG
and you want to get any blood related
test done which is necessary for the body, then is
it available in the policy
or not? On hdfcergo.com, an
individual
can get a free health checkup up to a maximum of ₹2000000 on the policy. Talking about ICICI Bank,
here the worth is up to 5000 at network
providers any time during your policy,
so here you can get your checkup done for up to 5000 for free. Talking
about Money Pal Sana, here an
individual can get a checkup up to 5000 and
if you have a family floater, then here
you can get your checkup done up to 10000, which is the
highest among these. Available in Bajaj A  There
is an optional cover, for this
you will have to pay extra premium and if we
talk about Niva Bhupa, here it is 5000 per person
and family, if it is a family floater
plan then here the maximum is ₹1000000
under the policy, here you can get your free
health checkup done, now let's talk about
e-consultation, it means that if you
want, you can consult a doctor through video call while sitting at home, so in
ADFC AGO, here once per
insured person for 51 defined major
illnesses, here one person can consult a
doctor for 51 defined major illnesses, there is a list of these, if you want,
this plan is not available in ICICI Lamba, if you want in Money Pal
Cigna, you
can consult a doctor unlimited times,
this plan is also not available in Bajaj Allians
and in NB also you get the
option of unlimited,
now let's talk about claim paid within three
months
How much percentage do they pay on the claim made by them, with in
three months it is
8.50, it has been
shown, now if we talk about my personal
opinion, then I found Money Pal Signa better
because here you are getting a lot of
things in a low premium,
here inside your piggy bank, here
you get up to 1000% sum insured,
with time which is guaranteed and if you
want to take insurance of any company, you
want to take a policy and in that you want ₹
5500000 and you get a discount, you
can take it from any company,
I will provide it to you at a rate lower than the market,
you just have to send a message on the number you see on the screen,
this offer will be valid only
for our 100 members, so hurry up, send a message on the
number you see on the screen